Conservative Party Inc. Collection
Conservative Party Inc. Collection
1962
Conservative Party, Inc.
0.5 linear ft. (SC)
Materials from the 1962 campaign including typescript speech by Kieran O'Doherty and David Jaquith. Candidates included David H. Jaquith (Governor), E. Vernon Carbonara (Lieutenant Governor), Kieran O'Doherty (U.S. Senator), Thomas D. Osle (Comptroller), and Frederick S. Denmin (Attorney General).
149194
Biographical History
Conservative Party Inc. (1962- ), or the Conservative Party of New York, is an American political party in New York State. The party was formed in 1962 in an attempt to counter the perceived liberalism of the Republican Party. The party continues to play a role in New York State politics today.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Conservative Party Inc. Collection contains a variety of materials related to the Conservative Party's 1962 campaign. Included in the collection are an Interview with David H. Jaquith, a Press release announcing Jaquith's nomination, campaign literature, and copies of Speeches given by Jaquith and Kieran O'Doherty, as well as a series of Correspondence. All material dates back to 1962.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is divided into 5 series: Correspondence, Interviews, Press releases, Printed material, and Speeches. Within each series, the material is arranged chronologically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Politics, government and public administration; O'Doherty, Kieran.; Jaquith, David H.; Conservative Party, Inc.; Political parties -- New York (State); New York (State) -- Politics and government; Correspondence.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - 17 Jul 1962, carbon copy of letter from Keith R. Snelson to Governor Rockefeller; 2 pages (Sc 234, Folder 1)
  - 18 Jul 1962, typescript letter from Frank J. Keneston to Editor, Post Standard, Malone, N.Y.; 2 pages (Sc 234, Folder 1)
  - 20 Jul 1962, typescript letter from Jerome Jones to Editor, Post Standard; 1 page (Sc 234, Folder 1)
  - Aug 1962, mimeographed letter from R. Wayne Archer to parishioners in Carillon; 2 pages (Sc 234, Folder 1)
  - 10 Oct 1962, signed typescript letter from C. Leone Rowe to Editor, Post Standard; 1 page (Sc 234, Folder 1)
  - 17 Oct 1962, signed mimeographed letter from Douglas Caddy to Editor, Post Standard; 1 page (Sc 234, Folder 1)
  - 20 Oct 1962, carbon copy of an unsigned letter from Francis H. Aspinwall to Walter J. Mahoney; 2 pages (Sc 234, Folder 1)
- Interviews
  - Sep 1962, taped interview of David H. Jaquith with E. R. Vadeboncoeur on WSYR-TV; 1 copy of tape, 2 transcript copies (Sc 234, Folder 2)
- Press releases
  - "Conservative Party Names Jaquith to Oppose Rockefeller", mimeographed; 6 pages (Sc 234, Folder 3)
- Printed material
  - Campaign literature (Sc 234, Folder 3)
    - We've Been Asked, 1 copy (Sc 234, Folder 3)
    - Declaration of Principles, 1 copy (Sc 234, Folder 3)
    - The Conservative Party, 2 copies (Sc 234, Folder 3)
    - At Last, Make your vote count, 2 copies (Sc 234, Folder 3)
    - Support the Conservative Party Candidates, 3 copies (Sc 234, Folder 3)
    - Vote the Conservative Party, 3 copies (Sc 234, Folder 3)
    - Campaign Poster, 1 copy (Sc 234, Folder 3)
  - Clippings (Sc 234, Folder 3)
    - "Jaquith Answers Questions: Conservative Explains Position", 08 Sep 1962; Post Standard (Sc 234, Folder 3)
- Speeches
  - 22 Oct 1962, typescript copy of speech by Kieran O'Doherty at Madison Square Garden, New York; photocopy; 13 pages, 2 copies (Sc 234, Folder 3)
  - 22 Oct 1962, typescript copy of speech by David H. Jaquith at Madison Square Garden, New York; photocopy; 7 pages (Sc 234, Folder 3)
  - 3 Nov 1962, duplicated copy of speech by David H. Jaquith at Syracuse Press Club; 8 pages (Sc 234, Folder 3)